Let's take the rear exit.
Shirou!
What is it, Saber?
I'm surprised to
see Saber with you.
You...
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
Archer! What are you
doing showing up now?
The Distance Between Them
Isn't it obvious? I sensed a threat
to my Master and rushed to her side.
But it appears I was too late.
Yes, it's all over!
I'll fill you in on
everything that happened
while you were busy
taking your sweet time,
so stay put and listen!
Looks like I arrived at
the worst possible time.
You can say that again!
A Servant got eliminated,
and you show up after the fact?
All right, all right.
Next time, I'll rush
to your side at once.
So, which Servant
was eliminated?
It was Rider.
I don't know exactly what happened,
but she was probably taken out by Caster.
How spineless.
I suppose she
really was all talk.
Archer, Rider died
protecting her Master.
You are in no position
to call her spineless.
She was spineless all the same.
One who calls herself
a hero should at
least try to take her
opponent out with her.
That she went down without a fight
suggests she was unable to do so.
You insult the manner of her
death, and you call yourself a hero?
Well, hero or not, it stands
to reason that anyone who
isn't worthy of this battle
should be eliminated early on.
Well said.
In that case, do you
wish to fight me, Archer?
I am compelled by a
Command Spell not to do so.
And without the ability to fight
back, I would die just like Rider.
Is that in keeping with
your code of chivalry, Saber?
Archer, that's enough.
My alliance with Emiya-kun lasts until
we defeat the Master hiding at school.
Or what? Do you want to force me to
use another Command Spell on you?
Fair enough.
Saber is so noble and righteous
that I got carried away teasing her.
My apologies, Saber.
No, my behavior
was immature as well.
Out of respect for Rin, I
shall overlook your words.
Anyway, if we're going
to defeat Caster, the
first thing we need to
do is locate her Master.
And for better or worse, they
come to this school every day.
Rather than spooking them and putting
them on guard, we should let them be.
In other words,
after we identify the Master, we attack
before they can return to Ryuudou Temple?
Exactly.
But after a big ruckus
like this, won't they
deem it too risky to
keep attending school?
That's unlikely.
I doubt Caster's Master still
possesses a will of their own.
Knowing her,
her very first move was probably
to turn her Master into a puppet.
That makes sense.
Anyway, we'll continue our
investigation of the school.
When we locate
Caster's Master, we strike.
That sounds reasonable,
but how do we look for them?
That'll be our
homework for next time.
We're all tired.
Let's call it a day.
No, I can still...
Hey... Tohsaka!
Can't you see that
Archer's acting strangely?
Don't you remember
what happened yesterday?
We need to wrap this up now!
Okay, I get it! I'll go home.
I won't press the
point any longer.
See you tomorrow, then.
Oh, and good work today.
I could actually see you as
a Master, even if only a little.
Let's go, Archer!
I'll give you a proper
talking-to when we get back!
Ah, there it is.
The uncharacteristic lack of
verbal abuse was troubling me.
Now, look here. Do I
need to lay down the law?
You want to sleep in my room?
Of course.
To prevent last night's
disaster from reoccurring,
I will be sleeping in your room.
I trust you have no objections.
I do! Big ones!
When it comes down to it,
this is your fault for falling victim to
remote hypnosis from such a great distance.
I cannot protect you
from Caster's magic,
so the least I can do is stay
as close to you as possible.
Well, that is pretty
reasonable, but...
Look, tonight...
All right.
You can sleep nearby.
Good. That is the logical
course of action for a Master.
But only nearby.
How am I supposed to
sleep like this, you idiot?
It is the sixth day since the
commencement of the war.
You are the first to have
made their way here.
Can I take it that you are
withdrawing from the war, boy?
O-Of course I am!
What else can I do, die?
Without a Servant, I can't kill
anyone, and I'm no longer a Master!
I-I'm just an ordinary human.
If anything, I'm a victim!
Having people come to kill me when
I can't fight back would just be unfair!
What? Do you have
a problem with that?
Of course not.
You are the first to
withdraw from this war...
and the first person to use this
church's services since it was founded.
I will offer you
every hospitality.
What? You're saying I'm the only one
who's ever been knocked out like this?
My grandfather's gonna
kill me when he finds out!
This is all thanks
to you people!
You stuck me with that
crappy Servant, Rider!
Oh?
Then Rider was of no use to you?
Damn right!
After all I did for her, she
went and died like a dog!
Any other Servant would've
been way more useful!
Damn it, I did exactly
what Grandfather said!
My preparations were perfect!
But those bastards
got in my way!
It was two against one! Who
can win against those odds?
Yeah. It wasn't
my fault that I lost.
Their Servants were
better than mine! That's all!
And yet those bastards were looking
down on me with their smug expressions!
Shit!
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
Then are you saying that you
still have the resolve to fight?
You are most fortunate.
There happens to be
one available Servant.
And what do you think
that doctor said to me?
"It's rare to see someone
so healthy, Fujimura-san,
so perhaps you'd care to
donate some blood? Ho ho ho!"
I'm a patient too, damn it!
Unbelievable!
Gimme more!
Anyway, isn't it great
news that most of
them got away with
nothing worse than anemia?
They didn't have to
close the school, either.
True.
I'm glad that classes
will be held as usual, but...
It's a little strange.
Strange? How?
Even though it was
such a big incident,
they have no idea
what really caused it.
Something about chemicals in an
empty classroom on the first floor?
They spent all night scouring
the building from top to bottom,
and that's the only
lead they have.
But the students in the hospital
will be able to go home soon, right?
Yeah.
It'll differ from person to person, but
most will be able to go home today.
Ah, Sakura-chan included.
Oh, really?
If you have time, you
should stop by and say hello.
I bet she'll be
happy to see you.
T-Tohsaka?
There's definitely something
suspicious about Issei.
Suspicious? How so?
He could be Caster's Master.
Caster's made Ryuudou Temple her
base, and Issei comes to school from there.
Those things can't be unrelated.
Come on. It could
just be a coincidence.
What? You're taking
Issei's side, Emiya-kun?
It's not like that.
Come with me.
Just come on!
Tohsaka?
Look, I get it.
I get what you're trying to say.
So don't give me
that look, okay?
I don't know how to handle
it when you get all sulky.
I'm not sulking!
Either way, I can't imagine Issei working
with Caster to do those horrible things.
Have you forgotten what
Archer said yesterday?
About Caster
controlling her Master?
In other words, isn't
it possible that Issei
might not even remember
that he's a Master?
That makes sense, I guess.
You "guess"? Do you
have a better theory?
Well, no.
Fine. I'll check him out.
Don't worry! I'll do it!
I'll look into him.
Leave Issei to me.
I'll find out whether
or not he's a Master.
Trust me.
I won't hold back just
because he's a friend.
You know I wouldn't lie to you.
All right.
The moment you have any idea
either way, tell me at once. Got it?
Yeah. You have my word.
So how do you
plan to figure it out?
Um...
You aren't just going to
casually ask, "Hey, Issei,
are you a Master?"
straight to his face, are you?
Of course not. There are ways to find
out if someone's a Master without asking.
Emiya?
Issei...
Don't ask questions.
Just take off your clothes.
Wh-What did you say?
Are you mad?
Is this some new form of interrogation?
Are you gonna question me?
That's right. And you'll answer!
Just hurry up and strip!
Stop this, fool! You call yourself
the son of a warrior family?
Shut up and strip!
Oh, man. That's
a load off my mind.
What are you so pleased about?
And why did you make
me strip for no reason?
Oh, right.
My bad, Issei.
If even you realize what you did was wrong,
then I insist that you explain this folly!
Sorry. I can't give you the details, but
there was something I needed to make sure.
Now that I know, we're all good.
Say, Issei...
Have you noticed anything
strange at the temple recently?
Strange?
Can you think of anything
that isn't like it used to be?
Nothing in particular.
That mountain is the
very picture of tranquility!
Hey, Issei!
School has now ended.
NO ENTRY
Students are not permitted to
remain on campus after school hours.
Please return home at once.
She went home?
Yes, Tohsaka-san
left a while ago.
What the hell? She said
to report to her right away.
Tohsaka?
Hey, Tohsaka!
What are you doing here...
T-T-Tohsaka, w-w-wai...
Be quiet.
If you cause a
scene, he'll spot us.
Who'll spot us?
Move. Stick to the wall.
Boobs... Tohsaka, your...
I said to keep quiet.
There. In front of
Sakura's house.
See that weird
guy standing there?
Blond hair...
A foreigner?
Right. He's been watching the
Matou house for a while now.
He's coming!
I wonder if he's the guy who
was talking to Sakura earlier.
To Sakura?
Yeah. It seemed like he was
asking Sakura for directions.
W-Wait, what are you doing here?
I could ask you the same thing.
What's with the evil grin?
Nothing!
But that makes sense. Instead
of looking for other Masters,
you're more concerned
about that precious junior
of yours who always
comes over to help you.
I think I understand you a
little better now, Emiya-kun.
Don't be stupid.
I did check out Issei, but you left
before I could tell you how it went.
He's in the clear.
What? You already
looked into him, Emiya-kun?
I did. Issei isn't a Master.
Believe me or don't.
No, I believe you.
You aren't the kind
to lie, Emiya-kun.
If you say Issei's
innocent, then that's that.
But how did you find out?
I made him strip, of course.
I had him take off his top and
checked if he had any Command Spells.
So what are you
doing here, Tohsaka?
I was worried about Sakura too.
Well, we're kinda acquaintances.
Fuji-nee said she's
being discharged today.
She might be at home.
Oh.
Tohsaka? You're leaving?
There's something
I want to ask you.
Fine. What is it?
Um, hypothetically...
How do you think someone
would feel growing up
if they were given
away to another family
for adoption, without
any say in the matter?
Emiya-kun?
What kind of question is that?
If their new home was
nice, they'd be happy,
and if it wasn't so nice,
they'd be unhappy, right?
I see.
Yeah, you're right.
Why am I even asking
such an obvious question?
Let's brainstorm ways to
find Caster at school tomorrow.
Sure, will do.
Ow...
It's been a while since we
practiced kendo in the dojo, Shirou.
A while?
Even with as fine a
sparring partner as Taiga?
I guess it has been.
After Dad died, I
just kind of stopped.
That's right.
After Kiritsugu-san died, Shirou
barely touched his bamboo sword again.
It made me so sad.
Don't bring up the past now.
Hmph.
Oh, tales from
Shirou's childhood?
You wanna hear? Do you?
Yes. I am curious.
All right! Then I shall
tell you everything.
He was the most
adorable little boy.
He was so trusting of everyone,
and he'd instantly agree to any request.
But he had a strange
stubborn streak.
Once he'd set his mind on
something, he wouldn't budge.
I guess he was the polar opposite
of Kiritsugu-san in that regard.
Polar opposite?
Kiritsugu-san was the kind of guy
who simply accepted everything.
He thought good and bad were subjective.
A "what will be, will be" kind of guy.
However, if he saw someone
in need, he'd try to help.
And Shirou would always
try to mimic Kiritsugu-san.
His view was way more
black-and-white, though.
He'd go around and
beat up the town bullies,
saying, "It's wrong
to do bad things!"
Yep, even back then, Shirou
was already a champion of justice.
Why a champion of justice?
That's a hard
question to answer.
Because I look
up to it, I guess.
You look up to it?
To being a champion of justice?
Yeah, I guess.
Why is that?
Why? Well...
Shirou?
Sorry. I'm gonna
head back to my room.
What was that?
What am I afraid of?
Why a champion of justice?
The reason I want to be
a champion of justice...
Yeah.
Since you couldn't
do it, I'll do it for you.
I just wanted to
follow in his footsteps.
Unfortunately for you,
there's no such thing.
Let your ideals drag
you to your death.
Shut up.
How can you know unless you try?
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
We attack tonight.
That boy isn't a winner.
They are naught
more than sacrifices.
Weapons... I need
weapons that will let me fight.
You're such an irritating boy...
Perhaps I shall kill you.
The Fifth Contractor
Next Time